Guide to the David Sedaris Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
David Sedaris papers
1964-2017
GEN MSS 1515
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
17.83
(34 boxes)
Contains drafts and writings from numerous publications by David Sedaris including Holidays on Ice, Me Talk Pretty Someday, Naked, and Calypso, along with correspondence, artist books, personal papers and notebooks, photographs, press clippings, ephemera, and other papers by or relating to Sedaris' life and work.
Sedaris, David, 1956-
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Box 32 (audiovisual material): Restricted fragile material. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 33 (born digital): Restricted fragile material. Access copies of digital files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
Box 34: Restricted during the lifetime of David Sedaris. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased from Glenn Horowitz Bookseller, Inc. on the Sinclair Lewis Fund and the Edwin J. Beinecke Book Fund, 2018.
Arrangement
Organized into six series: I. Notebooks, 2004-2017. II. Writings, 1980s-2017. III. Personal Papers, 1964-1989. IV. Audiovisual Materials, 1990-2003. V. Electronic Media, 2007-2008. VI. Restricted Papers.
David Sedaris
David Sedaris (born 1956) is an American humorist, author, and essayist. He grew up in Raleigh, North Carolina and graduated from the School of the Art Institute in Chicago in 1987. His works include Naked, Me Talk Pretty One Day, and Calypso. Sedaris is also well-known for his many contributions to This American Life, a weekly radio show on National Public Radio.
Content Description
The collection consists of writings, correspondence, personal papers, artist books, printed material, audiovisual materials, electronic files, and other papers by or relating to David Sedaris.
Memoirs -- United States; Writers, American -- 20th Century; American literature -- 21st century; American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American; Radio programs; Humorists -- United States -- 20th Century; Humorists; Essays -- 20th Century; LGBTQ resource; Gay authors; Gay men -- United States; Gay men -- 20th Century -- Archives
- Notebooks, circa 2004-2017; Series I; 3.25; (3 boxes)
  Arrangement
  Materials within this series are arranged chronologically with undated materials placed at the end.
  Scope and Contents
  Notebooks contain personal notes by David Sedaris.
  - Notebook, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2008; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebook, 2009 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2010; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebook, 2011 (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2012; 9 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2013; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2014; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Notebooks, 2014; 6 folders (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 2014-2015 (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, 2015; 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 2016 (Box 2)
  - Notebook, 2017 (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, undated; 15 folders (Box 2)
  - Notebooks, undated; 24 folders (Box 3)
- Writings, circa 1980s-2017; Series II; 8.83; (24 boxes)
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition.
  Contains materials related to David Sedaris's writings including drafts, galley proofs, research, notes, and other documentation related to the writing process.
  - Artist books, undated; 18 folders (Box 4)
    Contains artist books created by David Sedaris including Heels, Gilt By Association, Atlas, The Early Pilgrims, and Systems of Representation.
  - STH, undated (Box 5)
  - Jerry Springer piece for New York Times, 1998 (Box 5)
  - Title story--Dean Pope, circa 1992 (Box 5)
  - Twelve Moments in the Life of the Artist, 1996-09 (Box 5)
  - Title Poem From My New Book By The Same Name, undated (Box 5)
  - The Sporting Life with note to Ira Glass, 1999-02-04 (Box 5)
  - Jury Duty, undated (Box 5)
  - Proposals for Welfare Reform, circa 1998 (Box 5)
  - Early Chicago stories, undated (Box 5)
  - Story attempts France 97, circa 1997 (Box 5)
  - Smoke Free, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Cleaning, undated (Box 5)
  - The Pinetree Gang in Kathleen on the Carpet, undated (Box 5)
  - And that boy was Henry Kissinger, undated (Box 5)
    Typescript indicates this piece was co-written by "Davids Rakoff and Sedaris."
  - Heroes piece for BBC Radio, circa 1997 (Box 5)
  - Draft of flap text for "Holidays on Ice" with related correspondence, 1997 (Box 5)
  - Crop Duster piece for the New Yorker with notes, 2010 (Box 5)
  - Gifts For Him From Just Because, undated (Box 5)
    Includes copies of "Casting Call" by Amy Sedaris.
  - Rhyme diary, undated (Box 5)
  - Relationship Quiz by Amy and David Sedaris, undated (Box 5)
  - Sibling Rivalry, undated (Box 5)
  - Donna, the Christmas Whore draft, 1995-12 (Box 5)
  - Chicago stories, undated (Box 5)
  - Negative, 1998-03 (Box 5)
  - Fashion Victim, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Valentine piece for the New Yorker, circa 1997 (Box 6)
  - The Elfin Guide to Macy's Santaland and Puppet Theatre, circa 1985 (Box 6)
  - The Father Away, undated (Box 6)
  - Confidential Letter to Members of the Chudd County Pride Organization, undated (Box 6)
  - Swaddy letters, undated (Box 6)
  - Advertising, circa 1988 (Box 6)
  - Travel essay for NPR, 1993-08-02 (Box 6)
  - Giantess, 1990-10-07 (Box 6)
  - Goo with related correspondence, circa 1997 (Box 6)
  - To Ellen Back, circa 1996 (Box 6)
  - Crafty, undated (Box 6)
  - Incomplete quad, undated (Box 6)
  - You Can't Kill the Rooster/Silly P, circa 1998 (Box 6)
  - Guns, 1993-03-03 (Box 6)
  - Unidentified galley for story with annotations by Tom Prince, 1994-08-17 (Box 6)
  - Typescripts for Little Freida Mysteries, undated (Box 6)
  - Old Chicago stories, circa 1987 (Box 6)
  - Writing for "Travel and Leisure" article, 1997 (Box 6)
  - Writing for Slate diary columns, 1996 (Box 6)
  - Love Conn--Arts Club story, undated (Box 6)
  - Writing for Spin magazine, undated (Box 6)
  - Dix Hill for NPR, undated (Box 6)
  - Draft of Dean Pope, undated (Box 6)
  - Thanksgiving piece for NPR, undated (Box 6)
  - Yaddo diary, undated (Box 6)
  - Dear Mix draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Fatty Suit draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Barnes and Noble speech, undated (Box 7)
  - Knock Knock draft, undated (Box 7)
  - The Cobblestone draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Craig drafts, undated (Box 7)
  - Drafts for Cops, Speech to the Arts Club, and The Nutty Professor, undated (Box 7)
  - Ring of Dirt draft for BBC, undated (Box 7)
  - Today's Special draft for BBC, circa 1998 (Box 7)
  - Bonnie in New York draft for BBC, circa 1998 (Box 7)
  - At the Movies for BBC, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Rewrite of "Great Leap Forward" for BBC, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Atlas draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Orchid Show draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Second draft of "The Pirates in Men's Pants", undated (Box 7)
  - Typescript of story for Cheryl Tryku benefit event, undated (Box 7)
  - Exit 57 sketch draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Claws draft for BBC, 1998 (Box 7)
  - New York Lexicon for BBC, 1998 (Box 7)
  - Carefull draft for BBC, 1998 (Box 7)
  - NPR grad speech, undated (Box 7)
  - Where You'll Find Me draft, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Pine Tree Gang draft, undated (Box 7)
  - "Commandments" clipping and draft for Self magazine, 1997 (Box 7)
  - Godzilla vs. Me draft, undated (Box 7)
  - Sketches for Exit 57, circa 1994 (Box 7)
  - Christmas World draft, undated (Box 8)
  - Annotated story drafts, undated (Box 8)
  - Menfolk draft, undated (Box 8)
  - A Few Words to Booksellers draft, undated (Box 8)
  - Lawns draft, undated (Box 8)
  - Undecided fiction draft, undated (Box 8)
  - Draft of readings for book tour, undated (Box 8)
  - Attempts, undated; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Drafts, undated; 6 folders (Box 9)
  - Press and clippings for Talent Family productions and David Sedaris writings, circa 1993-1998; 2 folders (Box 10)
  - Chicago stories and drafts, undated (Box 10)
  - Correspondence related to Sedaris writings, 2000 (Box 10)
  - Resumes and writings by David and Amy Sedaris, circa 1992 (Box 10)
  - Diary drafts and excerpts, circa 2009-2014 (Box 10)
  - Arabesque drafts, undated (Box 11)
  - Leviathan drafts, circa 2014 (Box 11)
  - Clippings and press related to Sedaris writings, circa 1993-1998 (Box 11)
  - Je Parler Francais--Me Talk Pretty One Day French translation galley, undated (Box 11)
  - Drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Liz novel drafts, 2007 (Box 12)
  - Thanksgiving Versus Saint Patrick's Day, An Examination. By Stacy Case., undated (Box 12)
  - Science draft for New Yorker magazine, 1998 (Box 12)
  - Cobbler's Knob press and clippings, circa 1997 (Box 12)
  - Chipped Beef and other drafts, circa 1996 (Box 12)
  - Women's Open draft, undated (Box 12)
  - Interview questions and answers for Bon Appetit magazine, 2008 (Box 12)
  - Something for Everyone and other drafts, circa 1996 (Box 12)
  - Crop Dusters drafts, undated (Box 12)
  - Menfolk draft, undated (Box 12)
  - Make New Friends draft (never finished), circa 2002 (Box 12)
  - Drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Turtles (protest) draft, undated (Box 12)
  - Binghamton speech draft, undated (Box 13)
  - Bar Car drafts, undated (Box 13)
  - Book tour story drafts, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Undecided draft, 2008 (Box 13)
  - Understanding Owls draft, undated (Box 13)
  - Drafts, circa 2005-2009; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Socrates and Company draft, undated (Box 13)
  - Paola story draft, undated (Box 13)
  - Attempts, circa 2000 (Box 13)
  - C.O.G. and Naked drafts, undated (Box 13)
  - Stepping Out draft, undated (Box 14)
  - High Tides Low Expectations drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Cloud Gate draft, undated (Box 14)
  - Hustler draft, undated (Box 14)
  - Maui draft, 2004 (Box 14)
  - Move On Up a Little Higher and La Vie En Rose drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - I'm Still Standing drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Leviathan drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Silent Treatment drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Calypso draft, undated (Box 14)
  - Jokes, undated (Box 14)
  - Ug drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - People drafts and notes, undated (Box 14)
  - Family drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - Spirit World drafts, 2016 (Box 14)
  - One(s) Who Got Away drafts, undated (Box 14)
  - How Can You Laugh at a Time Like This? Easy! draft, undated (Box 14)
  - Drafts, undated; 4 folders (Box 14)
  - Death Knows No Season drafts and itinerary, 2016 (Box 15)
  - Sea Section draft, undated (Box 15)
  - Home Wreckers draft, 2016 (Box 15)
  - Innocents draft, undated (Box 15)
  - Drafts, undated; 5 folders (Box 15)
  - Why Aren't You Laughing draft with annotations, undated (Box 16)
  - Calypso stories drafts, circa 2016 (Box 16)
  - A Modest Proposal draft, undated (Box 16)
  - Carol draft, undated (Box 16)
  - Drafts, circa 2000s; 3 folders (Box 16)
  - Press and clippings related to Barrel Fever, circa 1992-1996 (Box 17)
  - Paperback copy of Barrel Fever and letter from publisher, 1995 (Box 17)
  - Correspondence and drafts related to Holidays on Ice, circa 1997 (Box 17)
  - Holidays on Ice page proofs, 1997 (Box 17)
  - Holidays on Ice drafts, undated (Box 17)
  - Holidays on Ice proof pages, 1997-1999 (Box 17)
  - Naked galleys and drafts, circa 1996; 4 folders (Box 18)
  - Naked press clippings, circa 1995-1997 (Box 18)
  - Santaland Diaries typescript pages, circa 1992 (Box 19)
  - Santaland Diaries draft, 1991 (Box 19)
  - Me Talk Pretty Someday typescript drafts and proofs, undated; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Me Talk Pretty Someday typescript drafts and proofs, undated (Box 20)
  - Me Talk Pretty Someday galley, circa 2000 (Box 20)
  - Squirrel and Chipmunk fables drafts, undated; 2 folders (Box 21)
  - Memory Laps and other drafts, undated (Box 21)
  - Attaboy and other drafts, undated (Box 21)
  - Untitled hippo fable draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Typing Chimps draft, undated (Box 22)
  - The Young Women drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Motherless Bear draft with annotations, undated (Box 22)
  - Rabbit and the Unicorn draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Sick Rat and the Healthy Rat draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Spider in the Bucket drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Clam and the Flounder draft, undated (Box 22)
  - City Mouse and the Heartland Mouse draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Goose and the Gander draft with annotations, undated (Box 22)
  - Single Celled Organism draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Ending drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Vigilant Rabbit drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Mouse and the Snake draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Grieving Owl drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Grieving Owl drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Restless Prairie Dog draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Ugly fox drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Mournful Bear drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Cow and Turkey drafts, 2008; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - Chicken drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Leech draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Parrot and Pot Bellied Pig draft, 2006 (Box 22)
  - Cat and Baboon draft, circa 2010 (Box 22)
  - Bear draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Crow and Lamb library draft, undated (Box 22)
  - Squirrel and Chipmunk (Doomed Love) drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Cat and Mouse (Hello Kitty) drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Drafts, undated (Box 22)
  - Let's Explore Diabetes with Owls drafts and galley, undated; 4 folders (Box 23)
  - Let's Explore Diabetes with Owls drafts, undated; 6 folders (Box 24)
  - Theft By Finding drafts with edits, undated; 2 folders (Box 25)
  - Theft By Finding drafts, undated; 3 folders (Box 26)
  - Drafts of stories already in books, circa 2006-2015 (Box 26)
  - Calypso stories drafts, circa 2015; 2 folders (Box 27)
- Personal papers, circa 1964-1989; Series III; 3.08; (4 boxes)
  Materials within this series maintain the original physical organization found at time of acquisition with the exception of some oversized materials.
  Contains materials related to David Sedaris's life and work including correspondence, juvenalia, ephemera, and clippings.
  - Clippings, ephemera, and slides, circa 1984-1989; 3 folders (Box 28)
  - Photographs, art, and ephemera, undated; 2 folders (Box 28)
  - Correspondence, ephemera, and juvenalia, undated (Box 29)
  - Report cards, clippings, and other ephemera related to David Sedaris's education, circa 1964-1981 (Box 29)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 29)
  - Reading and writing workbooks, circa 1960s; 2 folders (Box 29)
  - Grains of Sand, 1975 (Box 29)
  - Correspondence with friends, circa 1976-1981; 3 folders (Box 29)
  - Handmade language flashcards, undated; 11 folders (Box 30)
  - Slides, undated; 2 folders (Box 30)
  - Photographs including publicity headshots, undated (Box 31)
- Audiovisual materials, 1990-06-2003; Series IV; 1.08; (1 box)
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  Includes documentation of events and performances related to David Sedaris and his writings, as well as other pieces of media collected by Sedaris.
  - Jeopardy! episode featuring a a clue about "Me Talk Pretty Some Day", 2003; 1 (Box 32)
  - Jamboree--Theater for the New City, 1990-10-26; 1 (Box 32)
  - Working for Christmas, 1997-12-16; 1 (Box 32)
  - Hamrick, undated; 1 (Box 32)
  - Smoking--a short film by Matthew Modine, undated; 1 (Box 32)
  - David Sedaris/Cheryl Truyk, 1990-06; 1 (Box 32)
  - A. Bennett "Two in Torquay", undated; 1 (Box 32)
  - Tobias Wolff at Neeb Hall, Arizona State University--Three Stories plus Q and A, 2001-11-15; 1 (Box 32)
  - Unlabeled audiocassette, undated; 1 (Box 32)
- Electronic media, 2007-2008; Series V; 0.25; (1 box)
  Restricted fragile material. Reference copies of electronic files may be requested. Consult Access Services for further information.
  - This American life episode recordings, 2007-2008; 7 (Box 33)
  - New works by Kenneth Schorr, 2008; 1 (Box 33)
- Restricted papers, Series VI (Box 34)
  Restricted during the lifetime of David Sedaris. For further information consult the appropriate curator.